come on. let me show you my place, huh?
oh! i gotta tweet this.
no one will believe i'm with... the terrific nick.
uh, "authentic" nick.
not "terrific," okay?
i mean, uh... we're the best.
i'll bet. mm-hmm.
and it smells so good.
it does... smell good.
somebody here?
dad?
it smells like ribs. is that barbecue pizza?
no, we don't do barbecue pizza, all right?
that's for the hacks like terrific nick.
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
灵书妙探 第三季20集
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：
校对：
时间轴：60
ooh, nice and crispy.
just the way you like it.
you eat it. i'm not hungry.
you've never said no to turkey bacon.
what's wrong? nothing.
something.
don't make me tong you.
not even a smile. must be serious.
it's lauren's birthday party. i'm not going.
what? you been talking about that party for weeks.
"it's gonna be the party of the century." yesterday lauren came up to me,
and in front of everybody, told me i was disinvited.
it was humiliating. why would lauren do something like that?
she's one of your best friends. she was  one of my best friends.
i have no idea why she's acting like this,
and she refuses to talk to me, and ashley's still invited,
and so is everyone else.
and it's like i'm a social leper. well, ashley's not gonna go without you.
just because i have leprosy doesn't mean he should.
well, i think you should throw a rival party
and invite all your friends to that one instead. the party's tonight, and she has a live band performing.
i can't compete with that. well, then i'll call lauren's mom, and i'll--
you're joking, right?
what, so i can be a leper and a tattletale?
i'm 17. i can deal with this on my own.
it's just... every instinct in my body
is telling me to protect her.
yeah, but when it comes to teenagers,
not even you can protect her. alexis is gonna have to deal
with backstabbers her whole life.
but she's intelligent enough to rise above all of that.
i don't know. she looked like she was ready to commit murder.
speaking of murder.
i thought terrific nick's on the east side was number one.
uh, no, that's authentic terrific nick's.
this is just authentic nick's. this isn't terrific?
no, just authentic. it's also not terrific authentic nick's,
but that's across the street. what's the difference?
the difference is, this one has a dead body in the oven.
o-kay.
that is really... well-done.
another couple of hours, maybe, but luckily for me, he's only half-baked.
male, mid-40s, that's about as much i.d. as i can give you.
based on the oven setting and the body's core temperature,
i'd say he went in no sooner than 2:00 a.m. i'm afraid to ask. cause of death?
it wasn't the oven. the stab wound through the chest
says he was dead when he went in.
no sign of forced entry.
but we're running the prints on the door handle just the same.
all right. run 'em on the oven as well.
who found him? uh, nick jr.
unbelievable. give me his number.
authentic, not terrific.
no. i got no idea who he is.
i mean, i open up the oven, and bam--there he is.
and who were the last ones here last night? my dad and me.
we closed around 11:00,
and then i hit up the kaydar lounge,
met up with a lady friend, and then we came back here
to, uh... have a slice.
and when was that?
i don't know. 4:30.
where's your lady friend now? she was kinda throwing up a lot,
so the paramedics had to take her in.
oh, but i kept her number.
i-i don't think there's gonna be a second date.
yeah, you're right. i'm sorry.
i'm gonna need a list of all of your employees
and delivery staff. you don't think it was one of our guys in the oven, do you?
as soon as you get me that list, i'll start making phone calls.
i don't believe this.
you gotta be kidding me.
dad, these are the cops.
you must be authentic nick.
the one and only. nick?
i have the proprietor listed as ralph carbone.
yeah, that's me. everybody calls me nick. why?
because that's what everybody calls me.
i can't believe those bastards put a body in my oven.
i'm sorry, mr. carbone. you think that you know who did this? yeah, sure.
i'll bet it was that jackhole.
terrific authentic nick?
sal malavolta. he used to work for us years ago before opening
his own lousy pizza shop right across the street. he stole my friggin' recipes.
it's sal that done this, along with the other two.  the other two?
yeah, that vulture there. terrific nick?
vinnie delfino. and that dirtbag there.
and authentic terrific nick.  luca sabalini.
all three of them, they're thieves.
they live off our name, and they're not even real nicks.
i'm the only real nick. and your real name is ralph.
exactly. they been trying to run me outta dodge for years.
and now this. who's gonna buy my pizza now, huh?
hey! hey! you happy? i'm outta business!
mr. carbone, what makes you think that one of them did this?
a few weeks ago, one of them
snuck a gallon of soap into my secret sauce.
cost me a whole day of returned pies.
now look, uh, i may or may not have retaliated,
but if i did, them putting a cadaver in my oven
that's, uh, them retaliating back.
mr. carbone, that's not a cadaver.
what do you mean? it's a--they bor-- they--they got this from some medical school.
no, this isn't a prank. this is murder.
we got through to all their employees.
everybody's accounted for. lanie, what are the chances of getting an i.d.?
i'm not hopeful on fingerprints. we may have to wait
for a missing persons report and dental records. we also started a canvass
to see if anybody saw anything last night.
all right, let's get statements off all the employees, especially the ones with keys.
i'd like to know what they were doing last night.
shouldn't we look into the other nicks, too?  come on, bro. you don't really think
this is about some kind of pizza rivalry, do you?
competition to be the best in new york, clear animosity?
carbone said they'd broken in before.
if we are looking into everyone with access,
we should look into them as well. he's right, you know? pizza's serious business in this town.
all right. great. you talk to them. wait. me?
no, i... come on.
you know, you have to admit, a pizza oven--
very clever way to get rid of a body.
in "at dusk we die," i had my psychotic paralegal
kill her abusive boss and put him in a pottery kiln.
he was reduced to ashes in a matter of hours.
of course, you already know this, don't you?
that's probably what our killer planned on doing until nick jr. showed up. did i hear right?
you found a body in the oven at terrific nick's?
authentic nick's. authentic nick's?
oh, thank god. the wife loves terrific nick's.
i didn't have the heart to tell her it now came in full-bodied flavor.
oh, i liked it. i liked it.
so we ran through all of authentic nick's employees.
they alibied out, but i did find a bunch of stuff
on the other nicks. criminal complaints?
yeah, dozens of them filed back and forth between
all the nicks over the years-- bricks through front windows,
slashed delivery car tires, ooh, flaming bags of poo.
thank you. yep.
what, that's it?
flaming bags of poo, soap in secret sauces?
come on, castle. what do you think,
these guys suddenly graduated from frat pranks to murder?
beckett.
as expected, the body was too badly burned to get any prints,
but i did find this.
you see here where the shin bone should be?
those are titanium plates.
so killer cyborg sent from the future, resistance fighters intercept his coordinates,
redirect him into a pizza oven, saving humanity. the plates have serial numbers.
i ran 'em through the surgical database
and got an i.d.
gordon burns.
gordon burns? yes, castle, burns.
go ahead, make your joke. get it out of your system.
gordon burns, as in "new york ledger"? you know him?
well, not personally. he was a reporter.
i used to love his work.
did you find anything else on the body?
a melted cell phone belt clip, but there was no cell phone.
yeah, it wasn't at the crime scene, either.
and that's his wallet.
some credit cards,
driver's license-- that's all melted.
girlfriend, wife?
burns is listed as divorced, no next of kin.
he was a war correspondent, an investigative reporter.
what was he doing in a pizza oven?
maybe his editor knows.
we were friends, so when i became editor of the paper, he was my first hire.
the kinds of stories he wrote, he must have stepped on his fair share of toes.
not for years. he'd been out of the game for a while. why is that?
his kid was killed in an accident.
she was 10. after that, he finally gave in to his love affair with the bottle.
we see that you still had him on the payroll.
he did the occasional human interest story for our lifestyles section.
a waste of his talent, but it let him make rent, keep his insurance.
mr. shaw, was he working on anything recently?
just a puff piece i had assigned him last week. about what?
the pizza wars. you know, those authentic, amazing,
terrific guys always fighting over which one's the best.
it wasn't afghanistan.  but gordon was gordon.
he called a few days ago and said it was much bigger
than i thought. bigger how?
he didn't say, but i mean, it's pizza wars.
how big could it be? big enough to kill for.
let's dig deeper into all of the nicks-- terrific, authentic, and otherwise,
and let's also run background checks
on all of their employees. you know, this guy survived afghanistan,
the invasion of iraq, even tiananmen square, to be killed doing a puff piece on pizza?
it's like being a cop, bro.
you survive a firefight with a dozen armed gangbangers
only to be hit by a car
while writing a speeding ticket on the l.i.e.
hey, i ran a trace on burns' missing phone.
it's either out of battery or turned off.
all right, run l.u.d.s and financials. i want to
find out where he was and what he was doing last night. on it.
this has to be about something bigger than who has the best pizza.
you know, burns probably had notes and drafts of his story in his apartment.
if we can find them, we can figure out
what he was up to last night.  let's go.
door's been kicked open.
room's clear.
this place is trashed.
i'm gonna check with the neighbors, see if anybody heard anything. okay.
these drawers have been emptied.
if there were files or notes, they're gone now.
well, whatever he was working on,
someone didn't want us to find it.
you okay?
yeah. no, yeah.
i think i met her.
i went to a book signing of his, the one he did on the, uh,
sarajevo snipers.
she was...
coloring next to him while he was signing books.
he must have been a good writer for you to stand in line.
yeah. he was.
come on. let's go get c.s.u.
hey. i got something weird.
burns' neighbor, she says she's been holding
his mail for the last week. apparently burns told her
he was going out of the country for a while. out of the country? we know he's been here.
you know, that's the kind of lie that you tell people when you don't want anyone looking for you.
and if he's been staying somewhere else, there's a chance we could still find his notes.
i'm gonna to get ahold of his editor, find out where he might have been staying.
how does a story about pizza send somebody into hiding?
or get them killed? beckett.
hey. just got the c.s.u. report back.
the back doorknob of the pizza shop was wiped clean,
but they did find nick's prints all over the pizza oven.
well, that's to be expected. i mean, he worked there.
not authentic nick.
these prints belong to his neighbor across the street-- terrific authentic nick.
so, nick, or should i say sal?
know this guy? yeah, i know him.
that's the reporter doing the story on us.
and what did the two of you talk about?
who's the real nick, and i told him about my grandpa nick
and how he was an authentic ellis island immigrant
who was flipping his terrific dough on mott street the very day he arrived.
what else? that's it. why?
just doesn't seem like a good enough reason to kill.
kill? we found your fingerprints, sal, all over the oven.
you found my prints?
yeah.
so why don't we back up? and you tell us why you killed burns.
and this time, hold the extra cheese. i-i can explain.
i was there, but i didn't kill nobody.
ralph thought i was soaping his sauce,
so he broke into my place and took all the breakers out of my electrical panel.
now he's always bragging about his oven, so i thought i'd--
put a body in it.
no, steal it. i went over there a couple nights ago to see what i need to get it out.
you're kidding me, right?
i was in o'meary's on staten island last night, till closing.
okay? it was dart night. i took third place.
you want to look at somebody, look at ralph. why ralph?
what do you think, he makes that money with his crappy pizza?
he's connected. that's why i left.
all he cares about is laundering money for his wise guy pals.
you didn't happen to mention this to burns, did you?
as a matter of fact, i did.
money laundering? whoa.
we ran you through the federal database.
we know about the fbi investigation in the '90s
and about your connection to the spolano crime family.
my connection?
he's my second cousin once removed.
i see him at thanksgiving once every five years.
and the feds never found anything. the feds didn't, but maybe burns did.
so what happened, ralph? did he threaten to expose you?
you make him... disappear until your--your kid showed up
before that oven you're so proud of could finish the job?
i make money with my pizza.
you want to look at my books? go ahead.
you're gonna find exactly the same thing the feds found--
nada, zip, zilch.
sal put yous two up to this, right?
sal's the one brought the feds in in the first place, trying to shut me down.
you should be looking at him. sal had an alibi for last night.
what about you, mr. carbone?
i'm at home in bed. you could ask my wife.
and that reporter, all he asked me about was pizza.
that guy is guilty of something.
not until we have proof.
hey, ryan. any luck on where our victim was last night?
well, we're still waiting for info from his bank, but i got his luds.
nothing last night, and only a few calls to his editor in the previous days.
a reporter chasing down a story?
no, there should be dozens of calls. well, maybe he was making them from wherever he was staying.
any leads on the girl in the photo? no.
but i got in touch with burns' ex in portland.
they hadn't seen each other in years. yo. pay dirt.
i canvassed burns' building. at first, it was all,
"he's so quiet. he just keeps to himself."
but this other neighbor who just came home said that she saw burns and another guy having
a knock-down, drag-out yelling match just before he left.
about what? all she remembers is the other guy yelling,
"if you try to print that, i swear to god, i'll kill ya!"
did you get a description?
and i'll give you a hint. he's authentic...
and terrific.
so me and burns argued? so what?
it's a free country.
free speech doesn't cover death threats, mr. sabalini.
or murder. i told you, i was home last night.
yeah, you did, but your wife tells us a different story.
it seems she remembers you sneaking out before midnight,
after you thought she was asleep.
she told us you were off to see "that whore mistress of his over in flatbush,"
and when she confronted you about it this morning,
you told her that you went into the city because the store alarm was going off.
we checked. it wasn't.
so who were you lying to, luca, me or your wife?
my wife.
i was with angie last night. you can ask her.
i could. but it doesn't mean i'm gonna believe her.
what were you and burns fighting about?
he was gonna write something about me, destroy everything i've worked for.
i had to stop him. and what was he gonna write?
about my pizza.
about what makes my fat-free pizza taste so good.
it's made with real cheese.
there's nothing fat-free about it.
you were gonna kill for that? it's an expression.
besides, burns called me last night.
he said he'd consider not running it if i'd do him a favor. what favor?
hey, he didn't say what.
he was supposed to stop by today to talk about it.
you said that he called you yesterday? from where?
okay, got it. the incoming call on his cell
was from the hotel beta in midtown.
all right, let's go.
thanks.
paid in cash, signed in under the name melville.
this guy's definitely flying under the radar.
castle, there's his computer.
okay.
"new york's authentic terrific pizza wars."
sharp narration,
delicate prose.
this is not an expos?
it's a puff piece. well, i can practically smell the garlic,
but there's nothing in there that's about anything heavier than pizza.
or what got him killed. mm, his most recent notes.
pizza, recipes,
inter--
what? look at that.
4/3 @10pm
that's last night.
he was meeting with someone.
someone from that phone number, just before he was killed.
i'm gonna run that down. you have an app for that?
yeah, nypd issue. we just got it.
can i-- whoa.
fine.
then you don't get to play my "angry birds."
and they just came out with a new one.
"johnny farrell, swede anderson."
how do i know those names?
i don't know, but recognize this person?
that's the woman from burns' wallet.
bingo. monica wyatt.
and if she met with him last night,
she might be the last person to have seen him alive. i wonder if they went out for pizza.
little upscale for the pizza world. unless she's a middle man.
for the money laundering operation?
she transfers the assets out of country into swiss bank accounts using the names
johnny farrell and swede anderson.
or she's just a real estate agent as she claims to be.
oh, that's just her cover to avoid scrutiny with the feds.
you had a lot of imaginary friends growing up, didn't you? still do.
hi. can i help you?
i can't believe he still had this.
he actually took this on our first date.
and how long were the two of you together?
just a couple of months,
but god, this had to be three years ago.
i saw him once or twice after his daughter's accident.
he was different. it's like he just drifted away.
what made you see him last night?
i-i didn't see him last night.
well, according to his notes, he met up with you at 10:00 p.m.
well, that wasn't a meeting. that was a date.
but... he didn't show.  you said you hadn't seen him in years.
how did you end up on a date? we bumped into each other in the street the other day.
it was weird because...
it was in the village, and i never go down there,
and he said he doesn't go down there either,
but he was working on a story. did he tell you what it was about?
no.
how did he seem-- uh, worried, distressed?
he seemed like himself, like his old self,
like he was on to something.
he'd just come from the hall of records,
and whatever he found, he was really excited about.
the hall of records? yeah.
ms. wyatt, do the names johnny farrell or swede anderson mean anything to you?
i can't say they do.
monica wyatt... checks.
her brokerage house says that she complains
about commissions more than they'd like, but other than that, she's clean.
you find anything else in there? nope. the rest is just pizza.
i just got through burns' financials.
any activity last night? uh, yeah. something odd.
at 11:15 p.m., he used his atm card.
where? a not-so-good neighborhood about 15 blocks away from authentic nick's.
but here's the odd part--he never finished the transaction.
you mean he canceled it.
no, no, he never finished it. he popped in his atm card,
but then after about a minute of inactivity,
it ate his card. it's almost as if--
something happened. get atm surveillance. let's find out what.
i'm gonna go to the hall of records tomorrow morning
and see if we can figure out what burns was up to.
well... what happened?
alexis decided to crash lauren's party,
against our better judgment...
and i take it that the, uh, party crashing didn't go so well?
none of this would've happened if lauren wasn't
the most conniving bitch in the entire world. whoa.
it's warranted. when the band was performing,
lauren brought ashley up on stage with her,
and she kissed him in front of everyone.
bitch. how could she do this to me, to ashley?
what did ashley do? he was mortified. he ran off stage, and we left.
i mean, he was apologizing a thousand times and said
he had no idea that she was gonna do that.
it's like she's been trying to break us up this whole time.
it's been her master plan. well, she didn't succeed, darling.
you and ashley are stronger than ever, and--and she looks like a fool.
yeah, i wish that were true.
but according to the internet, ashley cheated on me.
she already posted the pictures of them kissing all over her web site.
it's a nightmare.
where's beckett?
oh, hall of records,
tracking down what burns was looking for. great.
listen... if i gave you a web site,
could you have your friends at tech hack into it and take some pictures down?
did someone find naked pictures of you again?
no, it's not me. it's alexis.
it's for alexis.
uh, this just got awkward. what's this about?
okay.
mean girl at school kiss-ambushed alexis' boyfriend
and then posted the photographic proof on her web site.
alexis... very upset. mm-hmm.
i-i could have my friend tony take care of it, you know, off the record. thanks.
and, uh, no need to mention this to beckett.
you know how she gets with these things.
yeah.
things like abusing police resources for your own personal agenda?
what?
that's ridic--no, you don't-- ab--no, that's--that's...
so, uh, what'd you find? anything on nicks?
uh, not exactly.
burns requested files relating to the 2003 murder
of a drug trafficker named harley romero,
a.k.a. harley playful, also known as handsome harley.
judging from those photos, i'm guessing it was ironic. what's a guy who's been dead for eight years
have to do with pizza? mm. hey, ryan.
yep. did you get a chance to look into all the nicks and their employees?
oh, yeah, just going over the reports right now.
mostly minor stuff. any drug charges?
no, nothing about drugs. romero? you think maybe
it's some kind of mafia tie-in with authentic nick's? according to the file, there's no connection
to any of the families. someone didn't like him.
it says here he was shot a dozen times, dumped in an oil drum, and set on fire.
yeah, word on the street was that a dealer killed him
over a turf war. so why was burns looking at him?
yo. bank just sent over surveillance footage. you guys gotta see this.
looks like he's running from something.
he's running from something all right. watch this.
he knows he's on camera. he's trying to tell us something.
he's writing it.
whoa! okay, take it back.
and freeze there.
he's got a knife.
he was trying to send us a message,
but he recorded his own murder. close up on the face.
castle, look at that face.
that's harley romero.
and he is very much alive.
why would he stop to write a message?
why not just keep running? well, that street empties on to a blind alley.
maybe burns thought he couldn't get away. any idea what he was writing there?
we're seeing if tech can enhance the image,
but we found no connection between this harley and the pizza joints.
maybe pizza has nothing to do with it.
maybe burns knew harley from an old story.
no. i-i don't recognize him at all.
did burns ever mention the name harley in any of his stories?
never. when this guy supposedly died,
gordon was embedded with the 2nd marine division in gulf ii.
mr. shaw, do the names johnny farrell or swede anderson mean anything to you?
yeah. they do.
they're both characters from old film noir movies. right.
uh, johnny farrell from the movie "gilda,"
glenn ford's character, and burt lancaster played
swede anderson in "the killers." and why would these two names be important?
this guy--harley--what kind of drugs was he dealing?
heroin, why?
because the only heroin story burns ever chased was the one that he could never finish,
about a high-end distribution ring in new york
that sets up shop inside legitimate businesses.
when someone needed product, they'd use a code word.
their code happens to be names of characters from film noir.
it's that story that destroyed him.
why? because of the guy who was behind the ring.
it was cavallo.
gordon burns was gunning for the prince of darkness himself.
who's cavallo?
it's a-a street myth, an urban legend.
anytime a dealer gets whacked, people always say it's cavallo,
but he's not even real.  oh, cavallo's real.
come on, shaw. we've all heard the scary stories.
i didn't. so the story goes that cavallo was mentored
by this badass colombian drug lord-- khazi "the conqueror"--
and eventually he put a bullet to his boss' head,
slit all of his kids' throats, and took over the operation.
but i mean, it's a fairy tale.
not to burns. not to his daughter.
burns told me he had a contact that was getting him close to cavallo.
the next day, he and his daughter are crossing the street, this car appears out of nowhere.
when he came to, his leg was shattered.
nina was 20 feet away, bleeding out, and he couldn't even crawl over to hold her,
so don't you tell me cavallo isn't real.
it sounds like burns was ahab and cavallo, his white whale.
well, he did sign in to the hotel as melville.
you know, it's that kind of sly humor that burns was known for.
and while i am loathe to profile,
the name cavallo--also the italian word for "horse"--
might suggest a link back to the nicks.
hey, ryan. when you were in narcotics,
when was the first time you heard the name cavallo? i don't know. probably around, uh, '03.
around all that time all those dealers were getting whacked. well, that's right when harley was killed.
so harley stages his own death,
brutally murders his competition,
and then starts a whisper campaign on the streets
about the new dark prince of heroin...
and a legend is born.  yo.
tech was able to blow up and enhance that atm video.
they're sending it up now.
i still can't make it out. mnh-mnh.
run it again.
can you flip it and slow it down?
yeah. what are you doing?
what i do best--writing.
okay, 3...
6... s...
that could be a 5. okay, s or a 5...
w-1-2... 7?
it's an address.
b... a... s? basement.
365 west 127th street, in the basement.
that's three blocks from the atm.
police! nobody move!
nypd!
room's clear. somebody moved out in a hurry.
coffee grinders for cutting. envelopes for packaging.
all the earmarks of a well-organized heroin processing house.
get c.s.u. in here. sweep the area.
if anyone saw anything, i want to know.
looks like your ahab found his white whale.
and it took him under.
hi, dad. bye, dad.
what, no kiss?
alexis, what happened to your face? nothing.
that's not nothing. what happened?
lauren. she cornered me in the bathrooms at school,
said i ruined her party, and then she accused me of hacking into her account
and deleting those pictures she took, as if.  and--and then what happened?
well, i called her a backstabber, and then she scratched me, so i...
you what? i punched her.
ah. what were you thinking?
i don't know. this isn't me.
i don't crash parties. i don't get in fights with people.
i... but, dad, she made me so angry.
i know she did, but retaliation is not the answer.
you get her back, she gets you back, and then one day, one of you ends up dead in a pizza oven.
is that what you want? look, the point is,
you're gonna have to deal with mean, backstabbing girls
your whole life.
you need to learn to be smart enough to rise above.
okay?
okay.
come here.
did you kick her ass? i kinda did.
good girl.
i should've gotten involved much earlier.
why? lauren would've still found a way
to make alexis' life miserable.
lauren isn't a criminal mastermind.
she's just a teenager. ah, castle,
never underestimate the power of a woman on a mission.
no, i don't. and i have the alimony checks to prove it.
beckett, just hung up with the lab.
that trace heroin from the processing house?
it matches most of the dope being peddled on the lower east.
any word on this harley? sir, if half of the rumors about this guy are true,
then he's got snitches all over the force,
so i was thinking of holding off on an a.p.b. until we knew more.
keep me posted. yes, sir.
you know, shaw said that cavallo is using legitimate businesses to distribute product.
you think he could be operating out of one of the nicks'?
yeah, but i can't get a warrant for a fishing expedition.
we're gonna have to have something more concrete. yo.
c.s.u. swept the tenement basement top to bottom, there's not one print anywhere.
any witnesses see burns getting chased?
in that neighborhood, nobody sees nothing.
but one of our uniforms did find this in a storm drain near the atm.
burns' phone? does it strike anyone else as strange
that a seasoned war correspondent would suddenly develop butterfingers,
drop his phone while being chased? you think he purposefully dropped it?
so that whoever was chasing him wouldn't get his phone? or what was on it.
the last call he made was 9-1-1
and he didn't press send.
outside the drug lab. he was casing the joint.
that's monica. she's involved.
monica wyatt, nypd! open up!
monica!
step back.
nypd!
monica.
he--he tried to kill me.
window.  let's go.
monica, who did this to you? if i tell you, then i'm dead.
i think we're past that. who did it?
cavallo.
i wasn't lying before about gordon.
we did date years ago, and i thought it was real,
but he was just doing it to get close to cavallo.
i never imagined that...
what's a midtown real estate agent doing mixed up with heroin dealers?
their labs are mobile.
they need new places for their processing centers every month or so, and i had
access to all the information that they needed.
look... this is not who i am.
i mean, i never meant for anything... how did it start?
i had some problems
a few years back.
i owed some people money.
a man came to me and he told me that he could make it all better.
i just... had to do a favor for him every now and then.
and at the time, that actually sounded harmless.
but this man knew things about me.
i mean things that nobody could possibly know.
and i wanted to leave,
but... after what happened to gordon's kid, i just...
gordon found me a couple of days ago.
he said he needed my help.
he said that i could end this, and that we both could be free.
all i had to do was take him there.
and now gordon is dead,
and i am next.
cavallo--who is he?
i've never seen him. didn't he just try to kill you?
if i knew who cavallo was, don't you think i would've told gordon?
i've only ever dealt with cavallo's right-hand man before.
that's who was here trying to kill me. and who is this man?
his name is harley.
him?
harley is cavallo.
so cavallo is hiding right under everyone's noses.
how do i find him? he finds me.
monica, gordon was right.
we can end this, but we need your help.
we believe that cavallo is trafficking drugs through a pizzeria, but we need to know which one.
i'm sorry. i don't know which one.
yo. we covered the whole area.
whoever he was, he's in the wind.
all right. why don't you guys take monica to the e.r.?
get her checked, and then get her over to narcotics.
let them talk to her. one last question--
johnny farrell and swede anderson?
that's how gordon got on to this story in the first place.
he heard somebody at one of the pizza joints using those names, and he knew it was cavallo's code.
those were last week's names. do you know this week's names?
no, but gordon said they were from his favorite film--
"the maltese falcon."
you're a sneak. what? i'm a what?
i don't care if these guys could've recognized you.
you hold 'em much longer, there's gonna be another murder on our hands.
relax. we're almost done.
we got two nicks down, two to go.
okay. call you in a bit. i wonder if i should've used sydney greenstreet's character-- kasper gutman.
now there's a guy who loved his pizza.
well, we already put our money down on bogie, so let's just play this through.
slice?
uh, no, a pickup actually for spade--
sam spade.
of course, mr. spade.
we have your order right here.
here you go, mr. spade.
we put it on your tab.
thank you.
winner, winner, pizza dinner.
possession, trafficking, conspiracy to distribute-- that right there
is 30 years, easy, sal-- 30 terrific authentic years.
it's life if you're an accessory to burns' murder.
no, i had nothing to do with that. i swear. you swear? so what are you trying to tell me?
are you trying to tell me that harley had the idea to put the body in your rival's oven?
you're a pizza man, sal.
body in an oven sounds more like you're speed.
no. no, no, no, it was him. it was all him.
so what, now you're a victim?
look, my place was struggling.
ame to me, he said the man that he worked for could help.
all i had to do was let him use my shop for a couple of months,
then he would make...
my dream come true.
your dream?
yeah, he said, uh, after it was over,
the man he worked for would, uh...
b-burn down authentic nick's.
this ain't me.
i never even smoked a joint.
but all those other nicks, the stuff they were doing,
it was driving me crazy. how did burns' body get in the oven?
harley called me that night,
said he needed to throw something in my oven overnight.
he didn't say what it was.
yeah, but you knew it wasn't a tray of lasagna. and i said no way.
no way. i never signed up for cremation services.
i never dreamed what i turned away
would end up in ralph carbone's oven.
you want our help, sal?
you want me to put in a good word with the d.a.? yeah.
then help me find him. help me find cavallo.
you can't find him.
he finds you.
that's not helping me, sal. you don't get it.
when i run out of product, i call him.
he delivers.
make the call.
harley romero, a.k.a., the legendary cavallo.
you won't talk without a lawyer.
with the evidence from the atm video and sal's testimony, he's gonna need one.
you know, it's brilliant when you think about it.
the unassuming middle man does all the dirty work
while everyone stays busy looking for the menacing mythic overlord...
who no one ever meets because he's not really real.
well, real or not, he's going away for a long time. good work.
narcotics is finished with monica wyatt.
she cooperated fully. okay, process her out.
and put a patrol car outside her building for the next few nights, just in case cavallo has friends.
what's up?
i was just thinking about burns, how close he came to catching
the guy who killed his daughter only to come up short.
well, if it's any consolation, there's justice now.
yeah. you know what's still bugging me? hmm?
the guy is running for his life, why does he ditch his phone?
well, he probably knew that he was gonna get killed,
and he wanted at least someone to know the truth. what truth?
it wasn't like there was a picture of cavallo on it. no, you're right.
the only person he had a picture of was...
just a few more questions, ms. wyatt.
i have been waiting over an hour.
you know the funny thing about this case is that
nobody is who they claim to be, not even you.
monica wyatt--it says here you moved to new york in 2002 from l.a.
yeah, so?
so we did a little bit of digging, and the only monica wyatt that we found
was a heroin addict who was shot point-blank
and then dumped in the l.a. river.
six months later,
word of a new and brutal kingpin started sweeping the streets.
and you're saying that's me?
i'm a real estate agent. have you seen my apartment?
oh, yeah, we saw that one.
but all of the other ones can only be previewed online.
what are you talking about?
your apartment sales to walter neff, frank chambers,
richard harland--they're all characters from noir films.
they aren't real.
you made millions in heroin holdings,
which you turned into millions in real estate holdings,
all clean. all the while, perpetuating the myth of cavallo.
gordon didn't die chasing a myth.
oh, yeah, gordon.
well, there's something that you didn't completely lie about.
you did meet him a couple of years ago,
but not as a boyfriend.
he was a pain-in-the-ass reporter that just kept getting a little too close.
until a car came out of nowhere and killed his daughter.
that got him out of your hair for a couple of years,
but then he caught your scent again at nick's pizza.
and that forced you to get rid of him permanently.
and then you fed us harley, the sacrificial lamb, to throw us off your trail.
harley attacked me.
oh, yeah, and then he managed to run down the fire escape
with such incredible speed that two of new york's finest detectives
were incapable of seeing him, never mind catching him.
beating yourself up...
was a nice touch.
you know what i just realized?
all those noir films that cavallo draws his names from,
they all have one thing in common--
a femme fatale.
i'd like my lawyer now.
ah, great. you're still up.
couldn't sleep if i wanted to.
that makes two of us.
is that from stefano's? mm-hmm.
you went all the way across the bridge for a pizza?
not for just anyone.
fresh basil and sausage.
any updates on, uh...
i called a mediation session with our school counselor today.
and it turns out, lauren was just jealous of all the time i was spending with ashley.
she thought i had ditched our friendship. so what'd you do?
we hugged it out.
and now you're friends again?
it's too soon to tell.
hurts like these...
take time to heal. time...
and pizza.
ooh, look at that.
cheers.
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入
来吧 我给你看看我的地盘?
我一定要发到推特上去
没人会相信我跟"棒尼克"在一起
是"真尼克"
不是"棒" 好吧?
我是说 我们才是最好的
我猜也是
真香哪
确实 很香
有人在吗?
老爸?
闻起来像排骨 是烧烤味的披萨吗?
没 我们才不做烧烤味的披萨呢 好吧?
只有像"棒尼克"这种冒牌货才这么花哨
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
灵书妙探 第三季20集
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：Moxiran  Wren 小冰
校对：还好我吃完饭了
时间轴：60
又香又脆哦
你最喜欢的哦
你吃吧 我不饿
你可从来不会拒绝火鸡培根的
- 怎么了?
- 没事
肯定有事
别逼我拿钳子来逼供哦
都逗不笑了啊 这事不小啊
是Lauren的生日派对 我不去了
什么 你叨叨了这个派对几个星期
- "这肯定会是这个世纪最好的派对"
- 昨天Lauren出现在我面前
当着大伙的面 告诉我 我被踢出受邀之列了
- 太丢脸了
- Lauren为什么会做这种事呢?
- 她是你最好的朋友啊
- 她曾是我最好的朋友
我也不知道她为什么要这样
她也不跟我说话 Ashley还在受邀之列
其他人也是
- 就好像我被驱逐出了社交圈的
- 那你不去的话 Ashley也不会去的
只是我被逐出来 不意味着他也要被逐出来啊
那我觉得你该开个竞争派对
- 邀请你所有的朋友来这个 不去那个
- 她的派对就在今晚 她还有一个现场乐队表演
- 我可比不上那个
- 那我跟Lauren的妈妈打电话 我--
你在开玩笑吧?
这样 我既被驱出社交圈 又成了个告密者?
我17岁了 我能自己应付这事的
只是 我身体在不停叫嚣
催促我去保护她
是啊 但事关少男少女事
你也不能保护不了她啊 在Alexis的一生中
她得应对各种暗箭伤人
但她有足够的聪明机智去应对
我不晓得啦 她看起来像是准备去杀人似的
说到杀人
我还以为东边角上的那家"棒尼克"才是最好的呢
不 那家是"好棒真尼克"
- 这家就叫"真尼克"
- 不是"棒"吗?
没 只有"真" 而且也不是"真棒好尼克"
- 那是街对面的那家
- 有什么区别吗?
区别就在于 这家烤箱里有具死尸
好吧
- 那还真是...
- 烤得很熟啊
也许得再烤几个小时吧 老天眷顾啊
他还没烤得太熟
男性 40多岁 我现在能给你的他的个人信息就这么多
根据烤箱的设置和尸体的核心温度
- 我得说他是在凌晨2点以后被放进来的
- 我还是得问一句 他的死因是?
不是烤死的 贯胸的一道刺伤
说明他被放进来时已经死了
没有硬闯的痕迹
但我们也在同样排查门把手上的指纹
好吧 也查查烤箱上的指纹
- 谁发现的尸体
- 这里的少东家
- 不可思议
- 给我他的号码
真的哈 可不是棒的哦
不 我不知道他是谁
我是说 我打开烤箱 砰的一声 他就倒在那儿
- 昨晚谁是最晚离开的人
- 我和我老爸
我们大概11点的样子关店
接着我去了Kaydar酒吧
遇见了个女人 接着我们就回来这儿
来 来"尝尝鲜"
那时几点?
我也不确定 4:30吧
- 你那位女朋友在哪儿呢
- 她吐了好久
所以医务人员就让她住院了
不过我留了她的电话号码
我看你俩不会有第二次约会了
- 是啊 你说得对
- 我很抱歉
我需要你家雇员们的清单
- 还有送货员的
- 你不是觉得烤箱里的是我们的人吧?
你提供给我这份清单 我就开始打电话确认
哦 我简直不敢相信
开玩笑吧
老爸 这些是警察
你一定是真尼克了
- 唯一货真价实的
- 尼克?
我看到业主的名字叫Ralph Carbone
- 是 就是我 不过每个人都叫我尼克
- 为什么?
因为每个人都这么叫我
我不敢相信 这些混蛋们居然放了一具尸体到我的烤箱里
- 抱歉 Carbone先生 你知道是谁干的吗
- 没错 我知道
我敢肯定是那个混球
"好棒真尼克"?
Sal Malavolta 他在对面开了自己那家烂店之前
曾为我工作了很多年 他还偷走了我的配方
- 肯定是Sal干的 跟那俩一起
- 另外两个?
- 是啊 那两个秃鹫
- 棒尼克?
Vinnie Delfino 还有那边那个杂碎
- 真棒好尼克
- Luca Sabalini
这三个人都tm的是小偷
盗用我们的名号 他们都不叫尼克
- 我才是真正唯一的尼克
- 可你的名字叫Ralph
就是啊 他们早就想把我挤出披萨生意
现在居然干出这种事 现在谁还会来买我的披萨呢 啊?
嘿 嘿 你们高兴啦 我没生意可做啦!
Carbone先生 你怎么会认为是这三人中的一个干的这事呢?
几周前 他们中的一个
偷偷放了一加仑的肥皂水进我的秘制酱汁里
让我家一整天都被退货
听着 我也许是以牙还牙了 也许是没有
但如果我做了 他们就放了具医用死尸进我的烤箱里
这是报复
Carbone先生 这不是具医用尸体
你是什么意思 他们不是从什么医学院里偷来的吗
不 这不是什么恶作剧 这是件谋杀事件
我们打通了他们所有雇员的电话
- 没人失踪
- Lanie 找到身份的可能有多大?
找指纹是没啥指望了
我们也许得等失踪人口报告和牙医记录出来
我们也开始查问昨晚有没人看到什么
好的 开始跟所有雇员做笔录 特别是那些有钥匙的
我想知道他们昨晚都在做什么
- 我们难道不该查查其他几个尼克吗
- 兄弟 你不会真觉得
这事关什么披萨竞争吧?
为了争谁是纽约最好的披萨哎 刀光剑影哦?
Carbone说过他们曾经溜进店里
如果我们在找那些有钥匙的人
- 那我们也该查查他们
- 他是对的 你知道吗 这座城市的披萨生意确实竞争激烈
- 好吧 你去找他们谈
- 什么 我?
别啊 我 不是吧
你知道 咱得承认 一个披萨烤箱--
是解决一具尸体的好办法
在我的书《死于黄昏》中 我让那个精神病法律助手
杀掉她那个爱骂人的老板
然后把他放进一个烧陶器的窑
他在几个小时之内就消解成一堆尘土
当然 你已经知道了 对吧?
- 咱们的凶手大概也是这么计划的吧 可惜少东家出现了
- 我没听错吧?
你们在"棒尼克"的烤箱里发现了一具尸体?
- "真尼克"
- "真尼克"?
哦 谢天谢地 老婆大人超喜欢棒尼克
我都不忍心告诉她现在有"烤全人"口味的了
[注：full-bodied意为浓香 此处为本义]
哦 说得很妙啊 我喜欢
我们查过了所有"真尼克"的雇员
他们都有不在现场证据
但我发现另一家"尼克"的雇员们就有些猫腻
犯罪投诉?
是啊 这些年来 两家尼克互相投诉
板砖砸前窗啊
划外卖车轮胎啊 丢便便燃烧弹啊
- 谢谢
- 好的
就这样算了?
便便燃烧弹 秘制酱汁里放肥皂?
Castle 你真觉得
这些人突然从恶作剧升级到谋杀了吗?
Beckett
正如我预料的一样 身体被毁严重 无法取得任何指纹
但我还是找到了这个
你看本该是胫骨的这个位置?
这些是钛板
所以机器人杀手从未来派过来
抵抗分子们截获了他的坐标
- 为了拯救人类 把他重调到一个披萨烤箱里
- 这些钛板有序列号
我在手术数据库里查了下
找到了此人身份
Gordon Burns
- Gordon Burns?
- 没错 是Burns[注:姓即为"燃烧"之意]
好吧 讲个笑话吧 别憋着呢
- Gordon Burns 是《纽约记事报》的那个吗
- 你知道他?
我不认识他 他是个记者
我以前很喜欢他的报道
你还在尸体上发现其他线索吗?
一个熔化了的皮带手机扣 但没发现手机
犯罪现场也没发现
这是他的钱包
几张信用卡
驾证....都化了
女朋友还是妻子?
资料中显示Burns离婚了 没有近亲
他是一名战地记者 一名调查记者
他跑到披萨烤箱里去干什么呢?
也许他的编辑知道
我们是朋友 所以我一当上报纸编辑
他就是我雇的第一个人
他写的这些报道 肯定让他一直如履薄冰吧
- 停了好多年了 他早已不干那类报道了
- 为什么呢?
他的孩子死于一场事故
她才10岁 之后 他终于将他一生至爱的事业束之高阁
我们看到你仍然在付他工资
他偶尔为我们的生活版写一些人情小故事
大材小用 但能让他付起房租 交得起保险
Shaw先生 他最近在准备写东西吗?
- 只有一篇我上周交给他的小故事
- 关于什么的?
披萨战争 你知道的 那些真与棒之间的战斗
争谁是最好的披萨店这种事
那不是阿富汗 但Gordon就是Gordon
他前几天给我打电话说
- 这事比我想的要大
- 怎么个大法?
他没说 但我想 就是个披萨战呗
- 再大能大到哪儿去呢
- 大到可以去杀人
让我们再深入调查下这些尼克披萨们吧
棒啊 真啊还有其他家的
也查查他们所有雇员的背景
你知道吗 这家伙从阿富汗
进军伊拉克 甚至天*安*门事件中都幸存下来了
却死于一场披萨战?
就像警察一样 兄弟
你经历了十几场黑帮交火
最后却在抄超速罚单时
被车撞到
嘿 我查了下Burn失踪的电话
要么是没电要么是关机
好的 查查当地用户数据和财务方面
- 我想找到他当晚在哪儿 做了些什么
- 马上去办
这事肯定不止是关于谁是最好的披萨店
你知道吗 Burns家里肯定有笔记 还有报道的草稿
如果我们能找到 我们就能知道
- 他昨晚是去干嘛的
- 那走吧
门被踢开了
房间里没人
屋子被搜了个底朝天
- 我去问问邻居 看看有没人听到什么
- 好
这些抽屉全被清空了
就算有文件或笔记 现在也没了
不管他现在在写什么报道
有人不想我们发现它
你还好吧?
是 不 是
我想我见过她
我去他的签售会
那本《萨拉热窝狙击手》
她在...
他签名的时候 她在旁边画画
他一定是个好作家 居然值得你去排队
是啊 他很不错
走吧 我们去拿犯罪现场报告
嘿 我发现些奇怪的事
Burns的邻居说她上周帮他收邮件
很显然Burns告诉他他要出国一段时间
出国? 我们知道他没出过
你知道的 这种谎话是你不想别人找你时候说的
而如果他一直待在别处的话 也许我们还有机会找到他的笔记
我去问问他的编辑 看能不能找到他可能待的地方
一个关于披萨的报道怎么会逼得一个人躲起来?
还导致他们被杀掉? Beckett
嘿 刚拿到犯罪现场报道
披萨店的后门把手上被擦得干干净净
但他们却在披萨烤箱上找到很多"尼克"的指纹
那不出意料啊 我是说 他就在那儿工作
不是真尼克家的尼克
那些指纹是他对街的邻居"好棒真尼克"的
Nick 还是该叫你Sal呢?
- 认识他吗
- 是 我认识他
是写我们披萨店报道的那名记者
那你们俩都谈了些什么?
谁才是真的尼克 我告诉他我的祖父叫尼克
而他是正宗艾里斯岛移民
他一踏进莫特街就开始做他棒极了的披萨
- 还有吗
- 就这些 为什么这么问?
看起来不值得去杀人啊
杀人 我们找到了你的指纹 Sal 布满了整个烤箱
你找到了我的指纹
是的
所以咱就别绕圈子了 你告诉我们为什么你要杀掉Burns
- 还有 隐瞒不报
- 我可以解释
我去过那儿 但我没杀人
Ralph认为是我往他酱汁里倒的肥皂
所以他闯进我的店里 拿走了我所有电路板的断路器
既然他每天都在吹嘘他的烤箱 所以我就想--
放具尸体进去
不是 是去偷它 几晚前我偷偷进去
查看下我要偷出来都需要些什么
你开玩笑吧?
昨晚我在斯坦顿岛上的O'MEARY酒吧呢 关门时才走的
好吧 那时天色已晚 我就去了别的地方
- 你想要查嫌疑人的话 就去查Ralph
- 为什么?
你认为呢 你以为他的钱是从那些难吃披萨里赚的啊?
他有背景的 这就是为什么我没干的原因
他只在乎给他的兄弟们洗钱
你没对Burns提过这些吧?
事实上 我提过
洗钱? 哇哦
我们在联邦资料库里查到了你
90年代那会FBI调查过你
你跟Spolano家族有亲密联系
我的联系?
他是我隔代的表亲
我每五年才在感恩节时见他一面
- 联邦调查局也没发现什么
- 他们没发现 也许Burns发现了
那到底是怎么回事 Ralph? 他是不是威胁要曝光你?
你就想让他消失
谁知道你的儿子出现了
你那部让你骄傲的烤箱却还没完成使命
我卖披萨挣钱
你想看我的账本吗? 看嘛
你会发现跟联邦政府调查的结果一模一样
完全 没有 问题!
Sal让你们来查我的对吧?
最初就是Sal把联邦政府扯进来 想害我关门
- 你们应该去查他
- Sal昨晚有不在场证据
而你呢 Carbone先生?
我在家睡觉呢 问我老婆就知道了
还有那个记者 他问我的都是披萨的事
这家伙肯定犯了什么事
可我们还没任何证据
嘿 Ryan 查到昨晚受害人的情况了吗?
还在等银行那边的消息 但我找到了他的电话记录
昨晚什么都没有 只有前几天跟他的编辑通过几次电话
一个记者在做新闻调查?
- 应该电话很多才对
- 也许他走哪都用公共电话联络
- 照片上的女孩有线索么?
- 没有
不过我联系到了Burns在波特兰的前妻
- 他们很多年没见了
- 哟 有发现
我细查了Burns的公寓 起初邻居们都说
"他很安静 不怎么跟人来往"
但有个刚回家的邻居说她看见Burns
在离开公寓前跟一个人有过激烈的争吵
- 关于什么?
- 她只记得另一个人在吼
"如果你敢发表 我发誓我会杀了你!"
有问到什么长相吗?
我给你个提示 他既"真"...
又"好棒"
我是跟Burns吵架了? 那又怎样?
吵架又不犯法
自由言论可不包括死亡威胁 Sabalini先生
- 或者谋杀
- 我说了 我昨晚在家
是 没错 但你妻子说的可不一样
貌似她记得你半夜溜出去了
你还以为她睡着了
她告诉我们你是去找"那个弗拉特布什的贱人"了
而且今早她当面问你
你告诉她你进城去了 因为店里有急事
我们查过了 并不是那样
那么你到底对谁说了谎 Luca 我 还是你妻子?
我妻子
我昨晚跟Angie在一起 你们可以去问她
倒是可以 但我不一定相信她的话
你和Burns都吵些什么?
他要报道我的事 毁掉我所有的努力成果
- 我得阻止他
- 他要写什么?
关于我的披萨
报道我的脱脂披萨为什么那么好吃
那就是用真正的芝士做的
一点儿也不脱脂
- 你为了这个就要杀人?
- 我是吓唬他而已
而且Burns昨晚还打电话给我
- 他说如果我肯帮个忙他就考虑不写了
- 帮什么忙?
嘿 他没说是什么
他原本今天要找我说这事儿的
你说他昨晚打给你了? 从哪打来的?
好的 有了 打给他手机的电话
是来自市中心的Beta酒店
好的 我们走
谢谢
现金支付 用Melville这名字登记入住
这家伙的确相当谨慎
Castle 他的电脑在这儿
好的
"纽约的好棒真披萨之战"
言语犀利
细腻的散文体
这不是揭露性报道
- 是一篇吹捧报道
- 我都能闻到大蒜味儿了
但除了披萨没有什么重要的内容
- 或使他被害的原因
- 他的近期备忘
披萨 食谱
联...
- 什么?
- 看看这个
时间是昨晚
他跟某人见面了
这就是某人的电话 就在他被杀之前
- 我查查这电话
- 你还有电话追踪程序?
对 纽约警局的 我们刚刚启用
- 我能不能...
- 喔
好吧
那我也不给你玩我的"愤怒小鸟"了
而且是刚刚更新的哟
"Johnny Farrell Swede Anderson"
这俩名字怎么这么耳熟?
不知道 不过这人认得出来吧?
就是Burns钱包里照片上的女人
对了 Monica Wyatt
如果她昨晚跟他见过面
- 她可能就是他生前最后见到的人
- 他们是不是一起去吃披萨了呢
- 作为披萨店有点儿太高档了吧
- 除非她是中间人
洗钱的中间人?
她把资金转移到瑞士银行帐户
用的是Johnny Farrell和Swede Anderson这俩名字
或者真的如她所言是个房产经纪人
噢 那只是她躲过联邦政府监视的幌子
- 从小到大 你有很多臆想出来的朋友吧?
- 现在还是多
嗨 有什么要帮忙的吗?
我真不敢相信他还留着这个
我们第一次约会时我送他的
那你们俩在一起多久了?
就几个月
可是 这照片应该是三年前的了
他女儿意外死亡后我们见过一两次
他变了很多 不怎么跟人接触
你昨晚为什么见他?
我 我昨晚没见他啊
可根据他的备忘 他昨晚10点跟你会面的
那不是会面 是约会
- 可是... 他没来
- 你刚说你几年没见他了
- 怎么突然又约会呢?
- 我俩有天在街上碰见
感觉很奇怪 因为...
是在附近的镇子里 我从来不去那儿
他说他也从来不去
- 但他是为了写一个报道
- 他有告诉你关于什么的吗?
没有
他看起来如何 嗯 焦虑 烦恼?
他就是他 还跟过去一样
好像在查什么东西
刚从档案馆过来
不知他查到了什么 他看起来非常兴奋
- 档案馆?
- 对
Wyatt小姐 Johnny Farrell或Swede Anderson
这两个名字你有印象吗?
恐怕没有
Monica Wyatt... 查清了
她的经纪人公司说她总是抱怨佣金太少
但除了这个 她就清白了
- 还找到什么了吗?
- 没有 剩下的都关于披萨了
嘿 我刚查到Burns的财政记录
- 昨晚有什么动静吗?
- 呃 有的 很奇怪
昨晚11点15分 他在自动取款机上取钱了
- 在哪?
- 距离"真尼克"15个街区远的一个破地方
但奇怪的是 他交易都没完成
你是说他取消了交易
不 不 是没完成 他把卡插进去
但好半天都没进行交易
所以卡被吃了 大概是...
- 发生了什么事
- 去找自动取款机的监视录像 我们就能查明了
我明早到档案馆去一趟
看看Burns到底去查了什么
- 那个...
- 怎么了?
Alexis还是去参加了Lauren的派对
出乎我们的意料...
看来派对搅和得不太成功?
如果Lauren不是世上最有心计的贱人
- 就什么都不会发生了
- 喔
- 让她发泄吧
- 乐队开始表演
Lauren就叫Ashley跟她一起上台
在所有人面前吻了他
- 贱人啊
- 她怎么能这样对我 这样对Ashley?
- 那Ashley什么反应?
- 他丢脸死了 跑下台去 我们就走了
然后他不停对我道歉
说不知道她会那样做
她一直都想把我们拆散
- 这就是她的大计划
- 可她并没成功啊 亲爱的
你和Ashley倒感情更好了 而且 这让她看起来很傻
对 我也希望如此
但我上网发现 Ashley欺骗了我
她已经把他俩接吻的照片贴在她主页上了
太可怕了
Beckett在哪?
噢 档案馆
- 去查Burns要找的东西
- 好的
听着... 如果我给你个网页
你能让你的朋友黑进这主页删几张照片吗?
又有人在网上发现你的裸照了?
不 不是我的 是Alexis
是为了Alexis
呃 我更听不懂了 关于什么的?
好吧
一个学校的坏女孩强吻了Alexis的男朋友
还把照片作为证据发在她主页上
- Alexis就... 非常难过
- 嗯
- 我可以让我朋友Tony帮忙搞定 你懂的 私下里
- 谢了
还有 呃 这事就别告诉Beckett了
你知道她会什么反应
好的
想滥用警力解决你的私人问题?
什么?
别逗了... 不 你不... 不是的 那个...
那么 呃 你找到什么了? 有关于Nicks的情况吗?
呃 没有
Burns去找关于一个叫Harley Romero的毒贩
在2003年被谋杀的资料
也就是Harley Playful 也被称为帅哥Harley
- 从照片看来 帅哥这说法是讽刺吧
-  一个死了8年的家伙
- 跟披萨有什么关系?
- 嗯 嘿 Ryan
- 什么
- 你有查这两家尼克店和他们所有雇员的资料吗?
噢 是的 我正在看呢
- 基本没什么大问题
- 有关于毒品的起诉吗?
- 没有 都跟毒品无关
- Romero? 你是觉得
- 某个黑帮跟"真尼克"扯上了关系?
- 根据资料看
- 跟任何黑帮都没有联系
- 有人很不喜欢他
这上面说他被打了好多枪 然后塞进油桶烧死的
对 传闻是某个毒贩
- 因为地盘之争杀了他
- 那Burns为什么去查他呢?
哟 银行把监视录像送来了 你们得过来看看
看起来他在躲避什么
他是在逃 看看这个
他知道自己在被拍摄 他想告诉我们什么
他正写下来呢
- 喔!
- 好的 倒回去
对 停在这儿
他有一把刀
他想告诉我们什么
- 却记录了自己被杀的过程
- 把脸放大
Castle 看看这张脸
是Harley Romero
而且他活得好好的
他干嘛停下来写东西?
- 而不是一直跑呢?
- 那街上空无一人 而且是死胡同
- 也许Burns知道自己逃不掉了
- 知道他在写什么吗?
我们在等技术科放大图像
但我们发现这Harley跟几个披萨店都没关系
也许披萨本就跟这事无关
也许是Burns老早就认识Harley了
不 我完全不认识这人
Burns有没有提到以前跟Harley有关的什么事情?
从没有 这家伙被认为死掉的时候
Gordon被分配到第二次海湾战争的海军2师
Shaw先生 Johnny Farrell或Swede Anderson
这两个名字您知道吗?
是啊 我知道
- 这两个都是老黑色电影里的人物
- 对啦
呃 Johnny Farrell是"吉尔达"里的
Glenn Ford主演的 而Burt Lancaster扮演了
- "杀手"中的Swede Anderson
- 这两个名字有什么重要呢?
这个Harley 他贩的是什么毒品?
海洛因 怎么了?
因为Burns唯一追查过的海洛因报道至今都没有完成
有一个毒品交易很广的纽约帮派
他们开店做些合法生意
有人需要买毒品时 他们就会用一种暗号
那些暗号恰巧就是黑色电影里的角色
就是那篇报道毁了他
- 为什么?
- 因为这帮派背后的人
就是Cavallo
Gordon Burns那是在太岁头上动土
Cavallo是谁?
一个街头神话 都市传奇人物
每当有毒贩被杀 人们都说是Cavallo干的
- 但他只是个虚构人物
- 噢 Cavallo是真实的
拜托 Shaw 我们都听过那些唬人的传闻
- 我没听过
- 传闻Cavallo是被那个哥伦比亚大毒枭
"征服者"Khazi一手带出来的
而后来他一枪打死了老大哥
割断了他所有孩子的喉咙 接管了他的生意
但我是说 那只是个神话故事
对Burns来说不是 对他的女儿也不是
Burns曾告诉我他有了一个机会接近Cavallo
第二天 他跟女儿一起在街上走 一辆车突然冒出来
他正要上前去 腿就被打断了
Nina就在20英尺外 血流不止 他都不能爬过去抱她
所以别跟我说Cavallo是虚构的
听起来Burns就像以色列之王 而Cavallo就是他的白鲸
他的确是用Melville这名字登记酒店
如今看来Burns成名的原因还真有点滑稽
虽说我不喜欢以貌取人
Cavallo这名字 在意大利语里是"马"的意思
或许跟两家尼克还是有关联呢
嘿 Ryan 你在缉毒组的时候
- 第一次听到Cavallo这名字是什么时候?
- 我不知道 大概在 03年吧
- 就是有好多毒贩被杀的那段时间
- 那就是Harley被杀的时候
所以是Harley自导自演假死
然后杀了他所有的竞争对手
然后到处散播谣言
说有一位新的大毒枭出现...
- 传奇就这样诞生了
- 哟
技术科放大优化了自动取款机录像
正送过来
我还是看不清
再放一遍
你能把画面一帧帧慢放吗?
- 好的
- 你干什么?
拿出我的强项 写
好的 3...
6... S...
- 也可能是5
- 好的 S或者5...
W 1 2... 7?
是个地址
B... A... S? 地下室
西127街365号 在地下室里
离自动取款机就三个街区
警察! 不许动!
纽约警察!
没人在 看来有人仓促逃离了
用于切割的咖啡研磨器 用于打包的信封
具备了一间井然有序的海洛因生产车间
所需的一切
让C.S.U.来清理现场
有情况马上向我汇报
看来你的以色列之王 找到他的白鲸了
还把他拖下水了
爸爸  嗨 老爹再见
不亲一个?
- Alexis 你的脸怎么回事?
- 没事
没事才怪 怎么了?
Lauren 她在学校的洗手间截住我
说我毁了她的派对 还指责我黑了她的账户
- 删了她的照片 说得像真的一样
- 然后呢?
我骂她卑鄙 她就抓我 我就...
- 你就咋样?
- 我就揍了她
哇 你怎么想的啊?
不知道 我不是这样子的
我既不会破坏别人的派对 也不会动手
但是 爸爸 她让我火冒三丈
我晓得 但报复并非解决的办法
你报复她 她报复你 终有一天
你们中的一个会死在披萨炉里
这是你想要的结果吗? 我想说
你这一生 要学会对付
很多小气而卑鄙的女人
你要放聪明一点 别跟自己过不去
好吗?
好的
过来吧
- 你有痛扁她吗
- 差不多吧
好样的
我应该早点干涉的
为何? Lauren迟早都会想出办法破坏Alexis的生活
Lauren没有高明的罪犯头脑
- 她只是一个青少年而已
- 啊 Castle
千万别低估一个有预谋的女人的能力
我不会的 手头上有大把赡养费支票为证
Beckett 我刚从实验室过来
我们在屋子里找到的海洛因
和下东区所兜售的大部分白粉相符
- 有关于Harley的消息没?
- 长官 如果关于这家伙的谣言有半数是真的
那么到处都布有他的耳目
所以我想 在得知更多情况之前
先暂停发布全境通告
- 随时向我汇报
- 是 长官
Shaw说Cavallo通过不法行业销售产品
你觉得他在利用其中一家披萨店?
嗯 但我们申请不到授权令去摸索情况
我们得找到更加确切的线索
C.S.U.把地下室翻了个底朝天
没找到任何指纹
有目击者见到Burns被追击吗?
街区里没人看到任何东西
不过有位警员在提款机旁边的下水道找到这个
- Burns的手机?
- 一个经验丰富的战地记者竟然会在
逃命的时候落下手机
- 不觉得很奇怪吗?
- 你觉得是他故意扔的?
- 所以追杀他的人就没法拿到手机
- 也无从知道上面的信息
他打的最后一通电话是911 但是没有拨出
这是在毒品制造所旁 他在监视披萨店
是Monica 她牵涉其中
Monica Wyatt
纽约警察! 开门!
Monica!
退后
纽约警察!
Monica
他 他要杀我
- 窗户
- 走
- Monica 是谁下的手?
- 我说出来的话就死定了
废话不说 是谁?
Cavallo
之前Gordon的事 我没有撒谎
我们之前是有约会过 我以为他真的喜欢我
但他只是为了接近Cavallo才和我在一起
我从未想过...
市中心的房地产经纪人为什么会和毒贩扯上关系?
他们的实验室是流动的
每个月都要换一次场所
我能拿到他们所需的一切资料
我不是这样的人
- 我从未想过...
- 这一切是如何开始的?
几年前
我遇到些麻烦
欠了别人点钱
有个人找到我 说他能帮我渡过难关
我只要时不时帮他个忙就好
那时候 一切看起来都是无害的
但是这人知道我的根底
了解一些旁人不可能知道的事情
我想离开
但是在Gordon的孩子出事之后 我...
几天前 Gordon找到我
说他需要我的帮助
他说我能结束这一切 然后我俩都能获得自由
我只要带他过去就好
现在Gordon死了 下一个就是我了
Cavallo是什么人?
- 我从未见过他
- 他不是要杀你吗?
如果我知道Cavallo是何人的话
我为什么不告诉Gordon?
我之前只和Cavallo的助手打过交道
- 也就是想杀我的那个人
- 他是谁?
他叫Harley
他吗?
Harley就是Cavallo
这么说Cavallo就藏在大家鼻子底下
我怎么可能找到他? 都是他找我
Monica Gordon说得没错
我们可以结束这一切 但我们需要你的帮助
我们认为Cavallo通过一家披萨店贩毒
但我们不知道具体是哪家
对不起 我不知道是哪家
这一带我们都搜过了
被他给跑了
好 你们带Monica去急诊检查一下吧
再送她去缉毒科
- 让他们跟她谈谈
- 最后一个问题
Johnny Farrell和Swede Anderson?
就是因为他们Gordon才被牵扯进来的
他在披萨店听到有人提到这个名字
就知道这是Cavallo的暗号
- 这都是上周用的名字了
- 你知道这周的吗?
不知道 但Gordon说都出自他最爱的电影
"马尔他之鹰"
- 你打小报告!
- 啥? 我咋了?
我不管这些人能不能认出你来
你再留着他们 我们手头上可能又多一桩命案
放轻松 就快完了
我们 查过了两家尼克 还有两家
- 好 待会儿再打给你
- 我在想我会不会用西德尼・格林斯垂的角色--Kasper Gutman
这是一个爱披萨的人
咱们都已经买定离手了
所以就走到底吧
来一片?
不 要外带的 给Spade先生
Sam Spade
明白 Spade先生
订单准备好了
Spade先生 给
我们给你记账上
谢谢
这下可好 披萨藏宝
藏毒 交易 阴谋销售
轻易就能判个30年 Sal 实实在在的30年啊
如果你和Burns的谋杀有关 那就是终生了
- 不 那和我没有任何关系 我发誓
- 你发誓? 那你打算如何解释?
你想说是Harley提的主意
把尸体放到你竞争对手的烤炉里吗?
Sal 你可是做披萨的
往披萨炉里放尸体这一招
对你很有利啊
不不不 都是他 全是他
这么说你是受害者咯?
我的店处境不好
然后他来了 他说他老板能帮上忙
我只需要把店借给他几个月
他就会帮我...
实现梦想
梦想?
他说结束之后
他老板会...
放火烧了"真尼克"
我原本不是这样的
我连大麻都没抽过
但那些披萨店的出现
- 快把我逼疯了
- Burns的尸体是怎么到炉子里去的?
那晚Harley给我打了电话
说他要往我炉子里扔点东西
他没说是什么东西
嗯 但你知道肯定不是一盘卤汁面条
我说没门 我可不提供火化服务
我没想到我拒绝的东西
到头来会出现在Ralph Carbone的炉子里
Sal 你想我们帮忙吗?
- 想让我们在检察官面前说些好话吗?
- 嗯
那就帮我们找到他 帮我们找到Cavallo
你找不到他的
都是他找上你
- Sal 这可帮不上忙
- 你不明白
货卖完之后 我给他打电话
他就送过来
那就打给他
Harley Romero 又名传奇Cavallo
没有律师在 他是不会开口的
我们有提款机的录像和Sal的证词
他是得请一个律师
你仔细想想 这样做还是很醒目的
一个低调的中间人打理所有的肮脏活计
大家却忙着寻找那个神秘而恐怖的幕后黑手
但是谁都没见过那人 因为他并不存在
不管真实与否 他都能避开很长一段时间 干得好
缉毒科已经审完Monica Wyatt了
- 她会全面合作
- 好 带她出来
在她的住所旁边安置一辆巡逻车
以防Cavallo在外有朋友报复
怎么了?
我在想Burns 他离抓住杀害女儿的凶手
仅一步之遥 却遇到了难关
嗯 现在终于能将其绳之以法了 总算是个安慰
- 你知道有件事始终困扰着我吗?
- 嗯?
他在逃命 为什么要扔掉手机?
嗯 或许他知道自己要遇害了
- 他希望有人知道真相
- 什么真相?
- 那上面连Cavallo的照片也没有
- 确实
那上边只有一个人的照片
再问几个问题 Wyatt女士
我都等了一小时了
你知道这单案子最有意思的是什么吗
涉案的人员都用了虚假的身份 你也一样
Monica Wyatt 这里说你是02年从洛杉矶搬来纽约的
是的 怎么?
我们稍微调查了一下 找到的唯一一个
Monica Wyatt
是一个瘾君子 她遭到近身射击
随后被扔进洛杉矶河
半年后
传言有一个残忍的新头目开始扫荡街区
你认为那是我?
我是个房地产经销商 你们不是去过我的公寓了?
嗯 我们见到那个了
但所有其他的只能在网上找到
你什么意思?
你的房子卖给了Walter Neff
Frank Chambers
Richard Harland 都是黑色电影里的人物
并不真实存在
你在毒品上赚了数百万
然后转为房地产资产
洗清自己 同时制造出Cavallo的神话
Gordon并非死于追逐神话
哦 是的 Gordon
你说的不全是谎话
你确实是几年前遇见他的
但你们不是情侣
他是一个你视为眼中钉的记者
拼命想要了解更多
直到从天而降的车祸终结了他女儿的性命
这件事让你清净了几年
但是他在尼克披萨店发现了你的踪迹
你不得不根除掉他
然后你搬出了牺牲品Harley 来帮自己脱罪
Harley袭击了我
是的 而且随后他从太平梯逃走
速度实在惊人 导致纽约最棒的两位探员
根本看不到他的影子 更别说抓人了
自己打自己
效果还不错
你知道我刚想到什么吗?
所有被Cavallo引用了名字的黑色电影
都有一个共同点
片中都有一位祸水红颜
我要见律师
很好 你还没睡
想睡的时候偏睡不着
我也一样
- 这是在Stefano买的吗?
- 嗯
你大老远过桥去买披萨?
不是谁都能享用到的
新鲜紫苏和香肠
那啥 有最新进展吗...
我今天和学校的辅导老师开了个调解会
原来Lauren是生我气
因为我经常和Ashley在一起
- 她觉得我重色轻友
- 那你怎么办?
拥抱解决了
然后你们又是好朋友了?
这还不得而知
这样的伤害
- 要靠时间来疗伤
- 时间...
还有披萨
看啊
干杯
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入